Inventory of the Bertha Warren Papers 1894-1908
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Bertha Warren Papers 1894-1908 1894 and 1895
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.110
0.25
Letters to Bertha Warren from her stepmother, Frances M. Warren, of Hartford County, Connecticut, and her friend, Edith Adam of Springfield, Hampden County, Massachusetts. Bertha Warren is a deaf student, about 20 years old, who attends the Mystic Oral School, later changed to Whipple Home School, in Mystic, New London County, Connecticut. The letters talk of skills that Bertha must learn, especially her art work, her activities, school and news from home.
Warren, Bertha; Adams, Edith; Warren, Norman W. arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 00/00/2008.
Biographical Note
She was born April 1875, the daughter of Norman Warren and the stepdaughter of Frances M. Warren. She lived in Hartford County, Connecticut. She attended the Mystic Oral School, later changed to Whipple Home School, in Mystic, New London County, Connecticut in 1894 and 1895. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Bertha Warren
Scope and Contents
Letters to Bertha Warren from her stepmother, Frances M. Warren, of Hartford County, Connecticut, and her friend, Edith Adam of Springfield, Hampden County, Massachusetts. Bertha Warren is a deaf student, about 20 years old, who attends the Mystic Oral School, later changed to Whipple Home School, in Mystic, New London County, Connecticut. The letters talk of skills that Bertha must learn, especially her art work, her activities, school and news from home.
Arrangement of Materials
Grouped by writer, then chronological within each group.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Mystic Oral School; Whipple Home School
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Geographic Name:
Connecticut--History--19th century.; New London County (Conn.)--History--19th century.
Topical Term:
Deaf--Education--United States.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Letters to Bertha Warren from her stepmother, Frances M. Warren., 1894-1896; id34176
  - 1894, id34179 (Folder 1)
  - 1895, id34180 (Folder 2)
  - 1896, id34181 (Folder 3)
  - Undated., id34182 (Folder 4)
- Letters to Bertha Warren, Kensington, Hartford County, Connecticut. From Edith Adam; Springfield, Hampden Co., Massachusetts., 1899-1908.; id34177
  - 1899-1908, id34183 (Folder 5)
- Norman W. Warren Papers, id34178
  - Additional Inventory of Estate of Norman W. Warren., 1876; id34184 (Folder 6)
  - Accounts and papers of Norman W. Warren., 1869 and 1873; id34185 (Folder 7)
- id34186